Guide to the Richard Moore Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Richard Moore papers
1940-2009
YCAL MSS 341
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
34.42
(43 boxes)
The collection documents the literary career and creative process of the poet and author, Richard Moore, and sheds light on his personal and professional relationships and interests. Papers include writing and professional files; correspondence and subject files relating to literary figures; drafts and manuscripts of Moore's poetry and prose; and manuscripts of writings by others. Also present is an extensive journal kept by Moore from 1956 to 2007, as well as other personal and family papers.
Moore, Richard, 1927-2009
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Richard Moore, 2009.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Richard Moore (1927-2009)
Richard Moore (Yale 1950) is the author of ten volumes of poetry; a novel, The Investigator (1991); a collection of essays, The Rule That Liberates (1994); and translations of Plautus's Captivi (1995) and Euripedes's Hippolytus (1998). Moore's books of poetry include The Mouse Whole: An Epic (1996), Pygmies and Pyramids (1998), and The Naked Scarecrow (2000). Moore taught at Boston University, Brandeis University, the New England Conservatory of Music, and Clark University. He led the Agape poetry series in Boston and The Poetry Exchange in Cambridge, Massachusetts and Leesburg, Virginia.
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the literary career and creative process of the poet and author, Richard Moore, and sheds light on his personal and professional relationships and interests. Papers include writing and professional files; correspondence and subject files relating to literary figures; drafts and manuscripts of Moore's poetry and prose; and manuscripts of writings by others. Also present is an extensive journal kept by Moore from 1956 to 2007, and other personal and family papers.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Files from Office/Bedroom Filing Cabinet, 1940-2009. II. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1940-2008. III. Writings, 1943-2007. IV. Journal, 1956-2007. V. Other Papers, 1940-2007.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Moore, Richard, 1927-2009
- Files from Office/Bedroom Filing Cabinet, 1940-2009; Series I; (7 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Files have been left in the order in which they were removed from the filing cabinets.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. consists of files removed from the filing cabinets located in the room which served as Moore's office and bedroom. Files contain drafts of writings, notes, correspondence, and other material broadly relating to Moore's literary endeavors and professional interests. File titles have been transcribed from the original folders, and the file numbering system is Moore's own, although it has yet to be determined what the letter and number sequence means.
  - F 32 Who is the Wind? (Box 1)
  - E1: T on Modern Poetry (Box 1)
  - E2: T on Mathematics (Box 1)
  - E3 The No Self, the Little Self (Box 1)
  - E4 Poetry, the Next Decade (Box 1)
  - E5: T on Science (Box 1)
  - E6: The Balancer (Box 1)
  - E7: 7 types of Accuracy (Box 1)
  - E8 ...Poetry from Musicians (Box 1)
  - E9: Short Pieces (Box 1)
  - E10: Fanatical Poets (Box 1)
  - E11: Of Form, Closed and Open (Box 1)
  - E12: How Heavy is Light? (Box 1)
  - E13: T on the Self (Box 1)
  - E14: T on Women and Marriage (Box 1)
  - E15: Short Pieces (2) (Box 1)
  - E16: Short Pieces (Box 1)
  - E17: Poets, Storytellers, and Scientists; Hobnobbing with Euclid (Box 1)
  - E18: Brecht and Rilke (Box 1)
  - E19: Milton, Satan, and Now (Box 1)
  - E20: COOP on RM, Martin, Green, DLB, Fondour (Box 1)
  - E21 Poetic Meter (Box 1)
  - E22 Words & Healing (Box 1)
  - E23 Classicism in Poetry, "Classicism" (Box 1)
  - E24 Kennedy Pieces / Captivi Intro (Box 1)
  - E25 W of A's (Box 1)
  - E26 Dante/Ivy League Fund Raising/Steele R/Emily 645/Dogs/Bennett (Box 1)
  - E27 New Classicists: RM / Pub'd E's / Spec History / Mayan Ruins / Toilets + Men (Box 1)
  - E28: Short Pieces (4) (Box 1)
  - E29 Kaddish/Baveds of Eupn Precocity in Economics Millan (Box 1)
  - E30 Memories of Robert Frost/Frost & Swift/Housman/Checkhov/Hopkins/Troll (Box 1)
  - E31 Salemi/Bennett/Stallings/Merwin/of Proofs/Schubert/Gore/GWhite (Box 1)
  - E32 Into Poets Meter (O.F.)/P. Contests (Box 1)
  - F2: Stories Published (Box 1)
  - Indexes (Box 1)
  - empty folder (Box 1)
  - Newman-Moore Interview (Box 1)
  - P1 The Embrace & Index (Box 1)
  - P2 Affluence (Box 1)
  - P3 For Gertrude (Box 1)
  - P4 Coming Clear (Box 1)
  - P5 Continuity (Box 1)
  - P6 A Reason for Living (Box 1)
  - P7 Pond Thoughts (Box 1)
  - P8 Pygmies (Box 1)
  - P9 The Spirits of Middle Air (Box 1)
  - P10 The Matchmaker's Art (Box 1)
  - P12 Blimps and Nightingales (Box 2)
  - P13 Poetry and Religion (Box 2)
  - P14 …Rita Hayworth (Box 2)
  - P15 (Box 2)
  - P16, 17, 18 (Box 2)
  - P19, 20 (Box 2)
  - P21 (Box 2)
  - P22, 23, 24 (Box 2)
  - P25–30 (Box 2)
  - P31–33 (Box 2)
  - P34–39 (Box 2)
  - P40–46 (Box 2)
  - P47–P53 (Box 2)
  - P54–P59 (Box 2)
  - P60–P67 (Box 2)
  - P68–P77 (Box 2)
  - P78–P81 (Box 2)
  - P82– (Box 2)
  - T1 (Box 2)
  - ND1 I19,20,21,22 (Box 2)
  - ND2 I23,24,25 (Box 2)
  - ND3 I26, 27 (Box 2)
  - ND4 I25, 29 (Box 2)
  - ND 5 I30, 31, 32 (Box 2)
  - Lists of Addresses (Box 3)
  - C1 Copyrights (Box 3)
  - C2 Contracts: Books, etc. (Box 3)
  - End board from book (Box 3)
  - C3 Grants, Awards, Colonies (Box 3)
  - C3a Djerassi Foundation (Box 3)
  - C3b NCCA & other colonies (Box 3)
  - C4 vacated (empty) (Box 3)
  - C5 English Mags, Pollinger (Box 3)
  - C6 Musical Settings (Box 3)
  - C7 Poetry Readings: Arrangements, Correspondence (Box 3)
  - C8 Poetry Readings: Notes (Box 3)
  - C9 Poetry Readings: Notices (Box 3)
  - C10 Publisher's Letters (Box 3)
  - C11 Endorsement Letters (Box 3)
  - C12 Student/Reader Letters (Box 3)
  - C13 Reviews of RM (1) Recent, 3 (Box 3)
  - C14 Blurbs/Prefaces (Box 3)
  - C15 Articles on RM (Box 3)
  - C16 Lists of Publications (Box 3)
  - Business cards (Box 3)
  - C17 CV & Bio/Who's Who (Box 3)
  - C18 Old CV's, Bios, Pubs (Box 3)
  - C19 Publishing Submissions (Box 3)
  - C20 Magazine Addresses (Box 3)
  - C21 Presses (Box 3)
  - C22 Consulting/Judging (Box 3)
  - C23 Teaching Jobs (Box 3)
  - C24 Writer's Conferences (Box 3)
  - C25 Reviewing: Bks, MSS, Mags (Box 3)
  - C26 Contests, Awards (Box 3)
  - C27 Circulation Lists (Box 3)
  - C28 Empires (Box 3)
  - C29 The Mouse (Box 3)
  - C30 Tristram's Rhapsody (Box 3)
  - C31 Archibald (Box 3)
  - C32 Alison's Friends (Box 3)
  - Photocopied covers: "Hellas" and "The Whole Mouse" (Box 3)
  - C33 Essays Book (Box 4)
  - C35 New Collection: Formation (Box 4)
  - C34 New Collection: Publication (Box 4)
  - C36 Children's / Light Verse (Box 4)
  - C37 No more Bottom/BB (Box 4)
  - C38 Captivi (Box 4)
  - C39 Hippolytus (Box 4)
  - Press Releases (Box 4)
  - PR (Box 4)
  - Slam (Box 4)
  - People (Box 4)
  - Translation Group (Box 4)
  - Council on Aging Po Gp (Box 4)
  - Parties (Box 4)
  - Teis Essay, etc. Freud letter (Box 4)
  - Photos & Mockups & Diagrams Originals (Box 4)
  - Copies of Books & Consignment Receipts (Box 4)
  - PEN American Center (Box 4)
  - Massachusetts Cultural Council roster review, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Poetry Society of America (Box 4)
  - New England Poetry Club, Academy of American Poets (Box 4)
  - Yale Alumni Loomis (Box 4)
  - Worksheets (Box 4)
  - Pew/New Yorker Advertising (Box 4)
  - Maling Lists (Box 4)
  - Homer Translation and Criticism (Box 4)
  - CVs and Clippings of Friends (Box 4)
  - BPL/AWP/WMBA (Box 4)
  - Anthologies: submissions (Box 4)
  - Spelling & Vocabulary Rhetoric (Box 4)
  - Lines (Box 4)
  - Names Titles; syllables & phon… (Box 4)
  - Aphorisms (& Old Sayings) Riddles (Box 4)
  - Magazine Pieces (Box 4)
  - The Imposter (Box 4)
  - Women The City (Box 4)
  - Greek (Box 4)
  - Bibliography (Box 4)
  - I Ching Divinations (Box 4)
  - Fiction Outlines and Fragments (Box 4)
  - Flavius (Box 4)
  - Ancestors (Box 4)
  - Chess (Box 4)
  - Music Notes (Box 4)
  - Notes made in Libraries, on Walks, etc. (Box 4)
  - Notes & Quotes on Reading and Viewing (Box 4)
  - Cassettes: Contents (Box 4)
  - Mouse I, II: Published (Box 5)
  - Mouse III, IV, V: Published (Box 5)
  - WH (Box 5)
  - QS I34,35,36 (Box 5)
  - Letters (Box 5)
  - Charles Martin (Box 5)
  - Art Mortensen (Box 5)
  - Mike Burch (Box 5)
  - Jonathan Holden (Box 5)
  - Dick Allen (Box 5)
  - David R Slavitt, 523 South 41st St Philadelphia, PA 19104 (Box 5)
  - Joe Kennedy (Box 5)
  - Tim Steele (Box 5)
  - Esther Cameron 3 (Box 5)
  - Richard Wakefield (Box 5)
  - John Mella (Box 5)
  - Jack Butler (Box 5)
  - Quarterlies A, B (Box 5)
  - Quarterlies C (Box 5)
  - Quarterlies D, E, F, G, H (Box 5)
  - Quarterlies I, J, K, L, M, N (Box 5)
  - Quarterlies O-Sa (Box 6)
  - Quarterlies Sc-Sp (Box 6)
  - Quarterlies St-Z (Box 6)
  - Atlantic, Harpers, NYKY, etc. (Box 6)
  - Old Poem Notes and fragments (Box 6)
  - Roome—ims (Box 6)
  - Sonnets: unused fragments (Box 6)
  - Poem beginnings and rejects (Box 6)
  - Inventions, etc. (Box 6)
  - Good Student Papers (Box 6)
  - Jokes & Oddities (Box 6)
  - Comic Strips (Box 6)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 6)
  - Comic Letters (copies) (Box 6)
  - Poems copied (Box 6)
  - Clippings for Fiction (Box 6)
  - Overheard Speech (Box 6)
  - Plans & Diagrams for Projects (Box 6)
  - Drawings (Box 6)
  - Mouse: Cancelled passages (Box 6)
  - Real Numbers: Further Sections and Prose, 3 (Box 6)
  - 2 square Theorems (Box 6)
  - Primes (Box 6)
  - Math Bibliography (Box 6)
  - The Art of Mathematics (Box 6)
  - Mathematics Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Electric Clock Symbols and Clippings (Box 6)
  - New Math Papers (Box 6)
  - The Real Number System (Box 6)
  - Math Papers (Box 6)
  - Excerpts from Books (Box 6)
  - Publisher Letters A–Do (Box 6)
  - Publisher Letters Dr–Ha (Box 6)
  - Publisher Letters Ho–L (Box 6)
  - Publisher Letters M-Prince (Box 7)
  - Publisher Letters Princeton-Sco (Box 7)
  - Publisher Letters Scr-Sta (Box 7)
  - Publisher Letters Sto-U.M. (Box 7)
  - Publisher Letters U.N.-Van (Box 7)
  - Publisher Letters Viking-Z (Box 7)
  - Old Agent Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Books U of Georgia Press (Box 7)
  - C 29 (2) Mouse: Countryman Correspondence (Box 7)
  - C 13 Reviews of RM (2) old (Box 7)
  - Old Mag A-D (Box 7)
  - Old Mag E-G (Box 7)
  - Old Mag H-K (Box 7)
  - Old Mag L-N (Box 7)
  - Old Mag O, Pl (Box 7)
  - Old Mag P-Sa (Box 7)
  - Old Mag Sc- (Box 7)
  - Old Mag T-Z (Box 7)
  - Anthologies: Permissions (Box 7)
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1940-2008; Series II; (12 boxes)
  Organized into two subseries: Personal Correspondence and Literary Correspondence and Subject Files.
  Series II. consists of correspondence with family and friends, and various sets of correspondence and subject files by and about various poets, authors, and other literary figures. Files include incoming correspondence, drafts and carbons of outgoing correspondence, clippings, reading announcements, and other material.
  - Personal Correspondence
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - 1944-1956, 18 (Box 8)
    - 1957-1958, 2 (Box 9)
  - Literary Correspondence and Subject Files
    Subseries contains several different alphabetical groupings that have not been organized into a single alphabetical arrangement.
    - Erhart, Betty, 1958 (Box 9)
    - "B", 1946-1958 (Box 9)
    - "C", 1946-1958; 3 (Box 9)
    - "D", 1944-1958; 2 (Box 9)
    - "E", 1948 (Box 9)
    - "G", 1946-1958 (Box 9)
    - "H", 1945-1953 (Box 9)
    - "K", 1946-1958 (Box 9)
    - "L", 1940-1956 (Box 9)
    - "Lib", 1957-1959 (Box 9)
    - "M", 1945-1958; 2 (Box 9)
    - "M", 1951-1956; 3 (Box 10)
    - "N", 1955 (Box 10)
    - "O-P", 1946-1952 (Box 10)
    - "R", 1946-1958; 2 (Box 10)
    - "S", 1947-1958 (Box 10)
    - "S", 1944-1951 (Box 11)
    - "V-W", 1944-1958 (Box 11)
    - "A-B", 2005-2009 (Box 12)
    - "B-C", 1999-2000 (Box 12)
    - "C", 1996-2005 (Box 12)
    - "D", 1993-2009 (Box 12)
    - "E-F", 1996-2006 (Box 12)
    - "G", 1996-2006 (Box 12)
    - "H", 1986-2007 (Box 12)
    - "J-K", 1988-2007 (Box 12)
    - "L", 1994-2007 (Box 12)
    - "M", 1997-2006 (Box 12)
    - "N-P", 1996-2008 (Box 12)
    - "P-R", 1996-2004 (Box 12)
    - "R", 1988-2006 (Box 12)
    - "S", 1993-2009; 2 (Box 13)
    - "S-T", 1978-2007 (Box 13)
    - "T-W", 1987-2004 (Box 13)
    - "W", 1985-2006 (Box 13)
    - "W", 1993-2008; 2 (Box 14)
    - "W-Z", 1995-2001 (Box 14)
    - "A - Arndt, W.", 1988-2002 (Box 15)
    - "Arnold, J. - Auchincloss, 1986-2009 (Box 15)
    - "Aylward - Barth, B.", 1977-2006 (Box 15)
    - "Bartruff - Berer", 1981-2001 (Box 15)
    - "Berer - Bliven", 1969-2001 (Box 15)
    - "Bloch - Brady", 1972-2001 (Box 15)
    - "Brennan - Burr", 1966-2004 (Box 15)
    - "Bush - Chou", 1968-1998 (Box 15)
    - "Christopher - Crawford", 1982-2002 (Box 15)
    - "Cunningham - Denman", 1985-2002 (Box 15)
    - "Denofsky - Eberhart", 1968-2000 (Box 16)
    - "Edelstein - Espaillat", 1968-2004 (Box 16)
    - "Falhoff - Fireman", 1979-1996 (Box 16)
    - "Fischer - Forti", 1977-2004 (Box 16)
    - "Fortunato - Gluck", 1972-2001 (Box 16)
    - "Goba - Haferd", 1960-2004 (Box 16)
    - "Halsted - Hart", 1962-1998 (Box 16)
    - "Hart - Herington", 1982-1996 (Box 16)
    - "Hiestand - Hodges", 1984-2000 (Box 16)
    - "Hoffenberg - Johnson", 1988-2006 (Box 16)
    - "Juster - Klappert", 1982-1996 (Box 16)
    - "Kraeft - Kris", 1983-2004 (Box 16)
    - "Krisak - Lake", 1966-1995 (Box 17)
    - "Langdon - Lewis", 1965-1997 (Box 17)
    - "Lightman - Locke", 1983-1998 (Box 17)
    - "Lockwood - Lund", 1982-1993 (Box 17)
    - "Lyle - "Marshall", 1984-1995 (Box 17)
    - "Maxson - Merrill", 1974-2002 (Box 17)
    - "Merritt - Mills", 1969-1996 (Box 17)
    - "Moore, B. - Morse", 1969-1997 (Box 17)
    - "Moylan - Muan", 1977-1998 (Box 17)
    - "Murphy - Nims", 1972-2003 (Box 17)
    - "Nisetch - Otis", 1968-1997 (Box 17)
    - "Ozersky - Pearson, N.H.", 1955-1995 (Box 18)
    - "Pease - Pritchard", 1968-1995 (Box 18)
    - "Probe - Randerson", 1965-2002 (Box 18)
    - "Rownan - Rose", 1963-2000 (Box 18)
    - "Rosen - Ryan", 1979-1996 (Box 18)
    - "Sadoff - Searle", 1980-2007 (Box 18)
    - "Seeley - Smith", 1960-1991 (Box 18)
    - "Soros - Sturman", 1969-1995 (Box 18)
    - "Sturrock - Trawick", 1966-1998 (Box 18)
    - "Trinity - Vitale", 1979-1995 (Box 19)
    - "Voight - Wheelers", 1965-2001 (Box 19)
    - "White - Williams", 1966-1998 (Box 19)
    - "Whitiker - Wood", 1966-1998 (Box 19)
    - "Work - Zoll", 1967-1996 (Box 19)
    - "Cook and Misc", circa 2003 (Box 19)
- Writings, 1943-2007; Series III; (16 boxes)
  Writings are not arranged in any particular order.
  Series III, Writings, includes drafts of poems and prose, notes, correspondence, and other material related to Moore's various literary endeavors. Also found are drafts of writings by others.
  - Science, Mathematics and Culture, 1970s-1990s; 4 (Box 20)
  - Annis, Claudia, Gary, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
  - Old mailing lists, 1970s-1980s (Box 20)
  - A Deep Discussion: An Opera, 1967 (Box 20)
  - FI: Stories for Mags (Box 20)
  - Tables of Contents, 1980s-1990s (Box 20)
  - Chocorua, 1970s-1997 (Box 20)
  - Writings (Letter file on desk), 4 (Box 21)
  - Blank stationery (Letter file on desk) (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, Jake Arnold (Box 21)
  - Press Releases (Box 21)
  - Mag Poems P1-P25 (shelf next to desk) (Box 21)
  - Mag Poems P26-P41, 2 (Box 21)
  - Mag Poems P42-P71, 2 (Box 21)
  - Mag Poems P72-, 2 (Box 21)
  - Musings, newsletter (Box 21)
  - Poems, old (Box 21)
  - Writings (Box 21)
  - Writings, "The Grass" (Box 21)
  - Letters, 1959 Jan–Dec (Box 21)
  - "A Bull by Candlelight" Poems (Box 21)
  - Letters, 1959 Dec–1962 Mar (Box 21)
  - Letters, 1962 Mar–1965 Summer (Box 21)
  - Letters, 1950 Sep–1957 Oct (Box 22)
  - Letters, 1957 Oct–1959 Jan (Box 22)
  - Letters, 1946 Jun–1947 Summer (Box 22)
  - Essays, 1954–1956 (Box 22)
  - Master's Thesis, Essays, 1956–1957 (Box 22)
  - Essays, 1948–1950 (Box 22)
  - Fiction, 1943–1949 (Box 22)
  - Pre Journal - Notes, Drafts, 1950s (Box 22)
  - Mathemathics Vol. I (Box 22)
  - Methematics Vol. II (Box 22)
  - Poem, untitled (Box 23)
  - The Oddball Rolls On, 2 (Box 23)
  - Various (Box 23)
  - Poems (Box 23)
  - The Dangerous Corner (Box 23)
  - Sailing to Oblivion (Box 23)
  - Various (Box 23)
  - Sailing to Oblivion; Rm 2 – Desk (Box 24)
  - Criticism and Reviews—Tearsheets; Desk – Rm 2 (Box 24)
  - Criticism and Reviews—Tearsheets; Rm 2 (Box 24)
  - Cover Art—"The Rule that Liberates" (Box 24)
  - Plates (Box 24)
  - Hippolytus (Box 24)
  - Author photos (Box 24)
  - "Misc materials related to Book publications and readings" (Box 24)
  - Tristram in Doubt, 4 (Box 25)
  - Tristram in Doubt (Box 25)
  - Tristram in Doubt, 2 (Box 26)
  - From office–on side table, 2 (Box 26)
  - Writings, 6 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence re: Writings, 4 (Box 27)
  - Tristram's Rhapsody vol. I (Box 27)
  - Tristram's Rhapsody vol. II (Box 27)
  - Writings: Alison's Friends, 4 (Box 28)
  - Writings, 6 (Box 28)
  - Tristram's Rhapsody vol. II (Box 28)
  - Claudia Annis (Box 29)
  - Vicky Madway, Hall/Moore letters, 1987–1994 (Box 29)
  - Donald Hall (Box 29)
  - Peter Heller (Box 29)
  - Eberhart Party—notes, 1982 Jun 9 (Box 29)
  - Personal ads (Box 29)
  - May Swenson (Box 29)
  - Nemerov (Box 29)
  - Lowell et al. (Box 29)
  - Letters, 1965–1979 (Box 29)
  - Wade & Cori Newman (Box 29)
  - Feirstein (Box 29)
  - Every Other Thursday Poets (Box 29)
  - Doug Knight (Box 29)
  - The Art of Enjoying Poetry. Goben Stair (Box 29)
  - Russian Novels (Box 29)
  - Gemini (Box 29)
  - J, S, T, C: cards, pictures, etc. (Box 29)
  - Cards from Girls (Box 29)
  - J. C. Whitney, 1976 (Box 29)
  - Literary Criticism (Box 29)
  - Modern Poetry/Milton (Box 29)
  - World Drama/Literary Criticism Notes (Box 29)
  - C4 Guggenheim Applications, 1970–1988 (Box 29)
  - Gerald Harnett (2) (Box 29)
  - Gerald Harnett (1) (Box 29)
  - XJ Kennedy, 1994 Dec 31 (Box 29)
  - Robert Flint (Box 29)
  - Herbert Morris (Box 29)
  - Leonard Nathan (Box 29)
  - Garrett (Box 29)
  - Judson Jerome (Box 29)
  - Lieberman (Box 29)
  - Wakefield (Box 29)
  - Katherine McAlpine (Box 29)
  - Old Phone Notes (Box 30)
  - John Mella (Box 30)
  - Sue Walker (Box 30)
  - Sam Gwynn (Box 30)
  - Neill Megaw (Box 30)
  - Crestview Regency Associates and Century Park (Box 30)
  - Letters (Box 30)
  - The Mouse, Book III manuscript (Box 30)
  - The Mouse, Books I and II manscript (Box 30)
  - The Mouse, Book IV manuscript (Box 30)
  - The Mouse, Book V manuscript (Box 30)
  - Harold G. McCurdy (Box 30)
  - Charles Martin (Box 30)
  - RP Dickey (Box 30)
  - John Mella (1) (Box 30)
  - John Mella (2) (Box 30)
  - Esther Cameron (2) (Box 30)
  - Esther Cameron (1) (Box 30)
  - Ellin Anderson (Box 30)
  - Bugeja (Box 30)
  - George P. Garrett (Box 30)
  - Warren Leamon (Box 31)
  - Citibank Correspondence, 2007 Jan 20 (Box 31)
  - BH early proof of Art's bad idea (Box 31)
  - Worksheets and Manuscripts, 1965 Sep–1967 Dec (Box 31)
  - Worksheets, 1960s–1970s (Box 31)
  - The Mouse Original Manuscript (Box 31)
  - Worksheets Cambridge, 1968–1971 (Box 31)
  - Worksheets Huntington, 1962-1965 (Box 31)
  - Clark University, 2000 (Box 31)
  - Clark: Student Poems Spring, 2000 (Box 31)
  - Epigrammatist selection (Box 31)
  - The Naked Scarecrow: Original MS. (Box 31)
  - Agape, circa 1995-2000 (Box 31)
  - "126-C. Ft Evans Rd.", 2003 (Box 31)
  - Alfred Dorn, 1980s-2000s (Box 31)
  - "From box of I.D. cards" (Box 32)
  - Writings, 2 (Box 32)
  - A Question of Survival (Box 32)
  - Memoir of a Pilot and Other Poems, 1966 Fall (Box 32)
  - Pigmies and Pyramids (Box 32)
  - The Naked Scarecrow and Other Disasters (Box 32)
  - How Seasons Run (Box 32)
  - The Broken Column (Box 32)
  - Tristram on Mathematics: A Poet's View (Box 32)
  - Sailing to Oblivion, proofs (Box 32)
  - "Buttoned in to History" and "The Rule That Liberates" (Box 32)
  - The Rule That Liberates (Box 32)
  - Essay Transcripts Returned (Box 32)
  - The Autobiography of a Mouse (Box 32)
  - The Investigator, 1990 (Box 32)
  - Tristram's Rhapsody: original manuscript and notes, 2 (Box 33)
  - The Investigator: original manuscript and some corrections, 2 (Box 33)
  - Alison's Friends: manuscript and notes - Stephanie's Synopsis, 2 (Box 33)
  - Mouse: original typescript and our first photocopy, 2 (Box 33)
  - Tristram's Attack On the Shelf - early versions (Box 33)
  - The Mouse Whole: final proof: 2 copies, 2 (Box 33)
  - Typescripts (Box 33)
    Includes: The Wisdom of the Ancients (5); Brecht and Rilke; Poets, Storytellers and Scientists; Some Table Talk for Mr. Moore; The New Forumalism: An Exchange; Confessions of an Amateur Mathematician; Review: Fables in Two Languages and Similar Diversions / Poems; Lyrics of Wit; Poetry: The Next Decade and Roundtable Essay for Hellas.
  - How Seasons Run: Martin's Selection, print-outs of Elegiac poem files (Box 33)
  - "Euclid", typescript, T. on Poetry, proofs (Box 33)
  - Education of a Mouse: 2 copies of galleys: 2 copies of typescript (Box 33)
  - Early draft of No More Bottom (Box 33)
  - Manuscripts: Burr, Homer, Gould, Archimedes, In Rome / Elegiac poems (P+P) and some short poems, 2 (Box 33)
  - The Autobiography of a Mouse (Box 34)
  - Various typescripts (Box 34)
    Includes: The Bawds of Euphony and the Prostitutes of Hope; Gogol's Overcoat; The Wisdom of the Ancients; The Foot in the Footprint; Tristram's Rhapsody and In Defense of Speculative History.
  - Worksheets, 1990-1992; 4 (Box 34)
  - Worksheets, 1988-1989; 2 (Box 34)
  - Worksheets, 1985-1987; 2 (Box 34)
  - Drafts of Poems (before 1962), 2 (Box 34)
  - Drafts of Poems (before 1962), 3 (Box 34)
  - Worksheets, 1982-1984 (Box 34)
  - Prose drafts - early 80s, 1980s (Box 34)
  - Worksheets, 1977-1981 (Box 34)
  - No More Bottom, proof (Box 34)
  - On Rhyme / Old Spec. History (Box 34)
  - BB and PP: Spare camera - ready print-outs from Lari Smith (Box 34)
  - Hippolytus: translations used (Box 34)
  - Gore & Waste Land / Stallings R. / Bennet R. / Ivy L. Fund Raising / W of A (11) / Freedom / ConTR / Troubadour (Box 35)
  - The Naked Scarecrow, proof / typescript (Box 35)
  - The New Classicists: RM, Hellas (Box 35)
  - Worksheets, circa 1992-1998; 3 (Box 35)
  - Sailing to Obvlivion (Box 35)
  - Published Essays: typescripts, proofs, 3 (Box 35)
  - The Broken Column, 3 (Box 35)
  - How Seasons Run: poems (Box 35)
  - The Mouse Whole (Box 35)
  - The Broken Column (Box 35)
  - The Marriage of a Mouse, 2 (Box 35)
  - How Seasons Run, circa 1985 (Box 35)
  - Pigmies and Pyramids, 2 (Box 35)
  - The Mouse Whole (Box 35)
  - The Real Numbers, 2 (Box 35)
  - The Rule That Liberates, 3 (Box 35)
  - Writings of Others
    - Various Authors, 1980s-1990s; 3 (Box 36)
      Includes work by: Ellin Anderson, Bill Barnum, Wendell Berry, Robert Barth, Harold Bond, John Butler, Jonathan Ceely, Bob Cogan, Jennifer Connolly, Susan Donnelly, Russell Edson, Kevin Johnson, Garrison Keillor, Michele Leavitt, Paula McCormick, Donna McKay-Randozzi, John Milton, Fred Muratori, Robert Phillips, Justin Ryan, Diana Sáenz, Leonard Trawick, Richard Waring, Anna Warrock, David Whitlock, Stephen Yenser, "Kraeft's Gazebo" and Fred Turner.
    - Nisetich, Frank, 2 (Box 36)
    - Archibald, Christine and John Ashbery (Box 36)
    - Various Authors, 1980s (Box 36)
      Includes work by: Ed Barna, Stephen Berer, G.F. Bush and Workshop Papers, and Dan Brown.
    - "Virginia Cazort's stories" (Box 36)
    - Various Authors, 1980s; 2 (Box 36)